Guide to the Irving Fisher Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- MICROFILM INVENTORY
  - Health Essays, Vol. VI: "General", 1924 - 1931
    - Omitted from previous volumes:
      - Quote from "Attitude of the College Man Toward Alcohol" (see Vol. IV, p 190) ( Christian Union Herald ), 1918 Jan 31 (Box 7)
      - Extracts from "Effect of Diet on Endurance" ( Good Health, Battle Creek, Mich.), Dec 1918 (Box 7)
      - Japanese reprint (In Eng.) of "The Modern Crusade Against Consumption," (1903) rec'd 1928 (Box 7)
    - 1924: (Tobacco) (Box 7)
      - "Seductive Wiles of MY Lady Nicotine" ( Independent, Dearborn, Mich.), 1924 Oct 11 (Box 7)
      - "Does Tobacco Injure Mental Efficiency" ( Independent, Dearborn, Mich.), 1924 Oct 18 (Box 7)
      - "Tobacco as Destroyer of City Property" ( Independent, Dearborn, Mich.), 1924 Oct 25 (Box 7)
      - Pamphlet reprint of 3 preceding items: "Tobacco, a Threefold Study," 1924 Nov (Box 7)
        - Same, printed by Dr. T. B. Bradford, Brinkley, Ark., 1925 (Box 7)
        - Same, reprinted by Board of Temperance., etc. Methodist Episcopal Church, Wash., D.C., 1928: (Box 7)
          - Pamphlet # 163, 1st title above (Box 7)
          - Pamphlet # 164, 3rd title above (Box 7)
          - Pamphlet # 165, 2nd title above (Box 7)
        - Extracts from pamphlet (p. 9) Central City, Neb., 1927 May 19 (Box 7)
    - Eugenics:
      - Extracts from "Impending Problems of Eugenics" ( Scientific Temperance Journal, Westerville, O.), 1921 Dec (Box 7)
        - Extracts from same ( Det Nye Nord, Copenhagen), 1922 Jul (Box 7)
      - Extracts from address at Battle Creek Sanitarium, 1923 Jul 28 (Box 7)
      - Report on Program of Eugenics Society ( Eugenical News, Cold Spring Harbor), 1923 Aug (Box 7)
        - Reprint of same, 1925 (Box 7)
      - Statement released to Associated Press, 1923 Aug (Box 7)
        - Extracts from same ( Det Nye Nord, Copenhagen), 1924 Nov (Box 7)
      - Letter to editor, correcting attitude of Eugenics Society toward Birth Control ( Call, N.Y.C.), 1923 Sep 15 (Box 7)
      - Letter to editor, also correction ( Courier, Buffalo), 1924 Jan 29 (Box 7)
      - "Eugenics," pamphlet reprint of section from 18th edition of "How to Live," 1925 (Box 7)
      - Extracts from radio talk (WBZ) re fitter families ( Union, Springfield, Mass.), 1926 Sep 16 (Box 7)
      - Report of President of Eugenics Society, 1926 Jun 26 (Box 7)
      - Seeking teaching jobs in England for 1973-74: résumés and correspondence, including with Gabbitas-Thring Services, individual schools, Anthony Chenevix-Trench [my headmaster at Eton, by this time at Fettes College, Edinburgh], and O.J. Wait [my house master from School House, Mill Hill School]; includes an explanatory note by me (Box 7)
      - 1925
        - "How I.F. Conquered the Dreaded T. B." ( Physical Culture ), 1925 Jan (Box 7)
        - "How to Live Long," revised, 1925 (Metro. Life Ins. Co.) (Box 7)
          - Same (Box 7)
            - Polish trans. (Box 7)
            - French trans. (Box 7)
            - Italian trans. (Box 7)
            - 2nd revised edition, 1927 (Box 7)
          - Extracts from same ( Masonic Review, N.Y.C.), 1926 May (Box 7)
        - "Why I'd rather be a Sanitarium Employee Than a Millionaire" ( Sanitarium News, B.C. Mich.), 1925 Jul (Box 7)
      - 1926
        - "If Youth But Knew," in Famous Features Syndicate Series ( Mercury Herald, San Jose, Calif.), 1926 Sep 15 (Box 7)
        - "Wagers Span of Life Will be 80 Years by End of Century" extracts from address before American Public Health Association ( Times, New York), 1926 Oct 14 (Box 7)
        - Interview on Longevity ( American, N.Y.C.), 1926 Oct 28 (Box 7)
        - "Lengthening of Human Life in Retrospect and Prospect," full address before American Public Health Association of Buffalo, 1926 Oct 13 ( American Journal of Public Health ), 1927 Jan (Box 7)
          - Reprint of same (Smithsonian Report for 1927), 1928 (Box 7)
          - Excerpt from same ( Childs' Restaurant Menu ), 1927 Oct 27 (Box 7)
      - 1928
        - The Wet Propaganda--Forecast for 1927 ( Christian Science Monitor, Boston, Mass.), 1927 Jan 18 (Box 7)
      - 1927
        - Address before Field Representatives of Metropolitan Life Insurance Co. Hotel Taft, New Haven, 1926 Nov 29 ( The Intelligencer (Metro. Life Ins. Co), 1927 Mar (Box 7)
        - Extracts from "The Influence of Flesh-Eating on Endurance," 1907 ( Vegetarian News, London), 1927 Jun (Box 7)
        - "Telling the World," brief quote ( News, San Francisco, Calif.), 1927 Aug 3 (Box 7)
      - 1929
        - "How to Fight Colds and the Flu," Memo from I.F. to his staff and other affiliated organizations, 1929 Jan 20 (Box 7)
        - "Personal Secrets of Health Revealed," Gorgas Institute, 1929 April release (Box 7)
          - Same ( Globe, Boston, Mass.), 1929 Apr 8 (Box 7)
      - 1930
        - "Economic Aspects of Health and Safety," radio address ( N B C ), 1930 Apr 25 (Box 7)
          - Reprint of same ( Safety Engineering, N.Y.C.), 1930 May (Box 7)
          - Same ( The Scovill Standard, Waterbury, Ct.), 1930 Oct (Box 7)
        - Review of: "The Money Value of a Man," by L.I. Dublin & A.J. Lotka ( Times Book Review, N.Y.C.), 1930 Jun 22 (Box 7)
        - "What Have We to do with Eugenics?" address at Eugenics dinner, N.Y.C., 1930 Mar 6 ( Eugenics ), August 1930 (Box 7)
        - "The Racial Aspects of War" ( Eugenics ), 1930 Nov (Box 7)
        - "Four Million Dollars Saved" ( Health ), 1931 May (Box 7)
        - Eugene Lyman Fisk, in Moriam ( How to Live, Journal of Life Extension Institute, N.Y.C.), 1931 Aug (Box 7)
  - Health Essays, Vol. VII: "Prohibition", 1922 - 1927
    - 1922 (Box 8)
      - "The Attitude of the College Man Toward Alcohol" (1915) ( Intercollegiate Statesman, Westerville, O.), 1922 Apr (Box 8)
    - 1923
      - "Students Urged to Hear Law Enforcement Talk," by Homer Cummings ( Yale News ), 1923 Oct 31 (Box 8)
      - Letter to editor re wine & beer amendment ( Yale News ) (Box 8)
    - 1924
      - Jan 25, 1924: Quote, in German ( Intercollegiate Statesman ), 1924 May (Box 8)
    - 1926
      - "Praises Volstead Law," extracts from testimony before Subcommittee of Com. on Judiciary, U.S. Senate ( Times, New York), 1926 Apr 18 (Box 8)
      - Letter to Editor, re "losses" from Prohibition ( Register, New Haven, Ct.), 1926 Apr 22 (Box 8)
      - "National Wealth & Prohibition" ( Republican, Springfield, Mass.), 1926 Apr 22 (Box 8)
      - 2nd testimony before Senate Judiciary Subcommittee ( Times, New York), 1926 Apr 25 (Box 8)
      - Interview re Six Billion Dollar Prohibition Profit ( Okmulgee Times, Oklahoma), 1926 May 13 (Box 8)
      - Letter to editor ( New Student, N.Y.C.), 1926 Jun 2 (Box 8)
      - Galley Release, extracts from "Prohibition at Its Worst," 1926 Sep 20 (Box 8)
        - Same ( Christian Science Monitor, Boston), 1926 Sep 20 (Box 8)
      - "Six Billions, Annual Saving by Dray Laws," extracts from address, Buffalo ( Christian Science Monitor, Boston, Mass.), 1926 Oct 11 (Box 8)
      - Ad for "Prohibition at Its Worst" ( Times, N.Y.C.), 1926 Oct 11 (Box 8)
        - Extracts from address on same, Center Church, Hartford, Oct 18, 1926 ( Post, Cambridge, N.Y.), 1926 Oct 22 (Box 8)
      - Extracts from Prohibition address, Brooklyn Jewish Center ( Times, Watertown, N.Y.), 1926 Oct 26 (Box 8)
        - Same, Standard Union, Brooklyn, 1926 Oct 26 (Box 8)
      - Extracts from Prohibition address in Toronto, Canada ( Mail, Toronto), 1926 Nov 15 (Box 8)
      - "Reply to Criticism of Prof. Wilcox" ( World, N.Y.C.), 1926 Nov 21 (Box 8)
      - Interview given United Press, N.Y.C. ( Post, Worcester, Mass.), 1926 Nov 20 (Box 8)
      - Address before Economic Club, N.Y.C. ( The Consensus, Natl. Econ. League) 1927 Jan (Box 8)
        - Excerpts from same ( Times Dispatch, Richmond, Va.), 1926 Dec 1 (Box 8)
        - Chart used in same (news release), 1926 Nov 30 (Box 8)
      - Extracts from address ( News, Dallas, Texas), 1926 Dec 1 (Box 8)
      - Extracts from address before Derby Board of Trade ( Evening Sentinel, Ansonia, Ct.), 1926 Dec 14 (Box 8)
    - 1927
      - "The Prohibition Controversy" ( American Year Book for 1926), publ. 1927 (Box 8)
      - "Alcohol," extracted from "How to Live," 18th Ed. ( World League Against Alcoholism ), 1927 (Box 8)
      - Paragraph quoted in leaflet "The Story of a Paying Investment" ( Scientific Temperance Fed, Boston), 1927 (Box 8)
      - "Prohibition at Its Worst," reprint of broadside ( National Advocate ), 1927 Jan (Box 8)
        - Same ( Moral Welfare, Pittsburgh, Pa.), 1927 Jan (Box 8)
      - Letter to Editor replying to critical letter of Jan 11, 1927 by Louis H. Porter ( Journal-Courier, New Haven, Conn.), 1927 Jan 14 (Box 8)
      - I don't Drink--Why ( Christian Advocate, Chicago, Ill.), 1941 Nov 20 (Box 8)
      - Release re deaths from alcohol poisoning ( Christian Science Monitor ), 1927 Jan 31 (Box 8)
      - Letter to editor re editorial ( Journal-Courier, New Haven, Ct.), 1927 Feb 15 (Box 8)
      - Letter to editor re 2 preceding articles ( Courant, Hartford, Conn.), 1927 Feb 26 (Box 8)
      - Extracts from book "Prohibition at Its Worst" ( The Pioneer, Brampton, Ontario), 1927 Mar 11 (Box 8)
        - Extracts from same ( Physical Training, Y.M.C.A.) 1927 Apr (Box 8)
        - Extracts from same ( Reformation, Stockholm), 1927 Apr 2 (Box 8)
      - Letter to editor defending Prohibition book ( Morning Advertiser, London, Eng.), 1927 Apr 1 (Box 8)
      - Extracts from address before Md. Conference of Maryland M. E. Church, Baltimore ( Times-Dispatch, Richmond, Va.), 1927 Apr 9 (Box 8)
        - Extracts from same ( Sun, Baltimore, Md.), 1927 Apr 9 (Box 8)
        - Extracts from same ( Banner, Nashville), 1927 Apr 10 (Box 8)
      - Letter to editor replying to review of "Prohibition at Its Worst" ( Sat. Review of Lit. ), 1927 May 7 (Box 8)
      - Prohibition broadcast of Greater Federation of Churches ( Post, Boston, Mass.), 1927 May 19 (Box 8)
      - Extracts from remarks before Ct. Div. of Woman's Nat'l. Com. for Law Enforcement ( Journal-Courier ) (Box 8)
      - Extracts from address at Law Observance Convention ( Journal Courier, Louisville, Ky.), 1927 Jun 7 (Box 8)
      - "Firm Dry Policy Urged" ( Christian Science Monitor, Boston, Mass.), 1927 Jul 16 (Box 8)
      - "Drunk Statistics in 500 Cities" ( Republican (letter to Editor) Springfield, Mass.), 1927 Sep 5 (Box 8)
      - Prohibition galley release, 1927 Sep 5 (Box 8)
        - Letter to Ed. re same ( Journal-Courier ), 1927 Dec 9 (Box 8)
  - Health Essays, Vol. VIII: "Prohibition", 1928 - 1933
    - 1928
      - "The Prohibition Controversy," reprinted from the American Year Book for 1927, publ. 1928 (Box 8)
      - Extracts from debate on Prohibition with W.H. Stayton at Men's Club, South Orange ( Herald-Tribune ), 1928 Feb 28 (Box 8)
      - Extracts from address at Conference on American Youth & Prohibition, N.Y.C. ( Times, Watertown, N.Y.), 1928 Mar 3 (Box 8)
        - Extracts from same ( Times, Brooklyn), 1928 Mar 4 (Box 8)
        - Extracts from same ( Times-Union, Rochester), 1928 Mar 5 (Box 8)
      - "Prohibition the Greatest Money Maker in World" ( Signs of the Times, Mountain View, Cal.), 1928 Nov 15 (Box 8)
      - "Prohibition Here to Stay," extracts from address, Central Baptist Church ( Courant, Hartford), 1928 Oct 29 (Box 8)
      - Newspaper release re "Prohib. at Worst," 1928 Nov 1 (Box 8)
      - Extracts from Prohibition address, Central YMCA, Brooklyn ( Eagle, Brooklyn, N.Y.), 1928 Nov 19 (Box 8)
      - Review of: "Prohibition: Its Industrial & Economic Aspects," by H. Feldman ( Polit. Science Quarterly ), 1928 December (Box 8)
    - 1929
      - "Presidential Surveys Proposed," from "Law Observance," (Durant Prize Essays) reprinted in Extension of Remarks of Sen. W. L. Jones. GPO, 1929 (Box 8)
      - Views on Effects of Prohibition after Nine Years, prepared for N.Y. Times ( Globe-Democrat, St. Louis, Mo.), 1929 Feb 3 (Box 8)
      - Extracts from Durant Prize Essay ( Register ), 1929 Apr 11 (Box 8)
      - "Can Prohibition Succeed?" a Socratic Dialogue with five others ( Forum, N.Y.C.), 1929 May (Box 8)
        - Excerpts from same ( Times Union, Albany), 1929 May 24 (Box 8)
      - "Should We Obey the Prohibition Law?" conclusion of Socratic Dialogue ( Forum ), 1929 Jun (Box 8)
      - Statement re Prohibition ( Standard-Examiner, Ogden, Utah), 1929 May 26 (Box 8)
      - News release replying to Asso. Vs. Prohib. Amendment, 1929 Jun 10 (Box 8)
        - Same (Box 8)
          - Courant, Hartford, Conn., 1929 Jun 10 (Box 8)
          - Christian Science Monitor, 1929 Jun 10 (Box 8)
          - Tribune, Capetown, South Africa, 1929 Aug (Box 8)
      - Extracts from address in symposium "Is Prohibition a Failure?" ( Times & Herald-Tribune ), 1929 Oct 14 (Box 8)
        - Same ( Post, Boston, Mass.), 1929 Oct 14 (Box 8)
        - Same ( Globe, Boston, Mass.), 1929 Oct 14 (Box 8)
      - Extracts from address, answering paper of Dr. John C. Gebhart, Washington, D.C., 1929 Dec 28 ( Register, New Haven & Post-Dispatch, St. Louis), 1929 Dec 29 (Box 8)
        - Same ( Times, New York), 1929 Dec 29 (Box 8)
    - 1930
      - "The Prohibition Controversy" ( American Year Book for 1929), publ. 1930 (Box 8)
      - Interview re Prohibition ( Christian Science Monitor, Boston, Mass.), 1930 Jan 28 (Box 8)
      - "Prohibition Not Crime Wave Cause" ( Telegram, Bridgeport, Conn.), 1930 Mar 1 (Box 8)
      - Statement re Prohibition ( Yale News ), 1930 Mar 13 (Box 8)
        - Another statement on same ( Harvard Crimson ), 1930 Mar 18 (Box 8)
        - Extracts from same ( Christian Science Monitor ), 1930 Mar 21 (Box 8)
      - Extracts from Sachem Hall address on Prohibition ( Yale News ), 1930 Mar 20 (Box 8)
      - Special article for Yale News, 1930 Mar 20 (Box 8)
      - "Drinking at Yale," reprint of portions of same (Box 8)
      - "Removes Doubts on Taft's Use of Glorious" ( Christian Science Monitor ), 1930 Mar 21 (Box 8)
      - Letter to editor re letter from Taft ( Journal Courier, New Haven, Conn.), 1930 Mar 26 (Box 8)
      - "21 Points" statement on Prohibition for Senate Judiciary Committee ( Civic League Record ), 1930 Apr (Box 8)
        - Same ( Times, N.Y.C.), 1930 Apr 3 (Box 8)
      - Extracts from address on Prohibition at home of Mrs. L.A. Frothingham ( Transcript, Boston), 1930 Apr 25 (Box 8)
      - "Is Prohibition Succeeding?" ( Presbyterian Magazine ), 1930 May (Box 8)
      - "Folly to Discontinue Prohibition Fight," extracts from address, YMCA ( Sentinel, S. Norwalk, Ct.), 1930 May 8 (Box 8)
      - "Exposes Wet Groups Behind Morrow," address favoring Franklin W. Fort for U.S. Senator, Elizabeth, N.J. ( Christian Science Monitor, Boston), 1930 Jun 12 (Box 8)
        - Same ( Union, Springfield, Mass.), 1930 Jun 12 (Box 8)
        - Same ( Times, Watertown, N.Y.), 1930 Jun 12 (Box 8)
      - "Dry Facts" ( Intercollegian ), 1930 Jun (Box 8)
        - Same ( The Christian, Kansas City), 1930 Jun 19 (Box 8)
      - Letter re interview given by Dr. Fisk when sailing for Europe ( Times, New York), 1930 Sep 2 (Box 8)
      - Statement re Roosevelt & Morrow on Prohibition ( Christian Science Monitor, Boston), 1930 Sep 11 (Box 8)
      - Comment on Tuttle's Prohibition statement ( Christian Science Monitor, Boston), 1930 Sep 17 (Box 8)
      - Reply to Bishop Fiske on Prohibition ( Daily Press, Utica, N.Y.), 1930 Oct 9 (Box 8)
      - Comments on Report of Asso. Vs. Prohibition Amendment ( Union Signal, Evanston, Ill.), 1930 Oct 18 (Box 8)
      - "Prohibition as an Economist Sees It," address over NBC network, 1930 Oct 18 (Box 8)
        - Same, Gazette, York, Pa., 1930 Oct 28 (Box 8)
      - "Prohibition in Dollars and Cents" ( Christian Century, Chicago), 1930 Oct 22 (Box 8)
      - Extracts from NBC address ( Union Signal, Evanston), 1930 Nov 1 (Box 8)
        - Similar letter re Dr. Fisk (p. 51) ( Transcript, Boston, Mass.), 1930 Nov 1 (Box 8)
      - Statement re Robert B. Binkley's book: "Responsible Drinking" ( Tribune, Minneapolis, Minn.), 1930 Dec 21 (Box 8)
    - 1931
      - "The Prohibition Controversy" ( American Year Book for 1930), publ. 1931 (Box 8)
      - Statement on Wickersham Report on Prohibition ( Register, New Haven, Conn.), 1931 Feb 2 (Box 8)
        - Same ( Courant, Hartford, Conn.), 1931 Feb 2 (Box 8)
        - Opinion (with 5 others) re Wickersham Report ( Review of Reviews ), 1931 March (Box 8)
      - Questions asked Henry Ford re Prohibition in relation to business, and replies ( Times, Hartford, Conn. & Times, New York), 1931 Apr 17 (Box 8)
        - Same ( The American Issue ), 1931 Apr 25 (Box 8)
    - 1932
      - Views of I.F. & others on Dry Issue ( The Philo Publishing Co., New York), 1932 (Box 8)
      - "The Prohibition Controversy" ( American Year Book, for 1931), Publ. 1932 (Box 8)
      - "The Proof of the Pudding - ," by Will R. Lucas, M.D. with quotes from I.F. ( Health & Efficiency, London, Eng.), 1932 Mar (Box 8)
      - "Legalizing Liquor, Direct Blow at Prosperity" ( Christian Science Monitor, Boston), 1932 Sep 21 (Box 8)
      - Excerpt from NBC address ( How to Live, Life Extension Institute, N.Y.C.) 1932 Nov (Box 8)
    - 1933
      - "The Prohibition Controversy" ( American Year Book, for 1932), publ. 1933 (Box 8)
      - "Arguments vs. Repeal" ( Journal-Courier, New Haven, Conn.), 1933 Jun 17 (Box 8)
    - 1932
      - Reviews of German Trans. of "The Noble Experiment" (Box 8)
    - General, 1937-1947
      - 1937
        - Notice of coming Health talk ( Star, Toronto), 1937 Feb 10 (Box 8)
        - Interview re Alcohol ( Star, Toronto), 1937 Feb 17 (Box 8)
        - "Longer Lives Seen Possible" ( Globe & Mail, Toronto), 1937 Feb 18 (Box 8)
        - "Expectancy of Life Seen Doubled" ( Star, Toronto), 1937 Feb 18 (Box 8)
          - Same ( Telegram, Toronto), 1937 Feb 18 (Box 8)
        - Address to Patients ( Sanitarium News, Battle Creek, Mich.), 1937 Jun (Box 8)
        - Account of Vitality Records office ( Times, N.Y.C.), 1937 Nov 7 (Box 8)
      - 1938
        - "Flesh-Eating & Endurance," reprint of Appendix 4, from "How to Live," 1938 (Box 8)
        - "Self Selection of Diet by Students," reprint of Appendix 5, from "How to Live," 1938 (Box 8)
          - "Food Tables," reprint of Appendix 9 from same, 1938 (Box 8)
          - "Some Examples of Vitality," Appendix 32 from same, 1938 (Box 8)
        - "Health is What You Make It" ( The Commentator, N.Y.C., Vol. 4, No. 4), 1938 Nov (Box 8)
        - "A Step Toward Livlier (sic) Old Age," account of Vitality Records office by Ray Giles ( Readers Digest ), 1938 Feb (Box 8)
        - Letter to Editor ( Sunnyside Rainbow, Indianapolis, Ind. (publ. by Sanitarium of same name), 1938 May (Box 8)
        - "Add Years to Your Life" ( Ledger Syndicate release, Phila. Pa.), 1938 May 1 (Box 8)
        - "You Can Live to be a Hundred," about Vitality Records by Wainwright Evans ( Physical Culture ), 1938 Jun (Box 8)
        - "Best Investment in the World" ( Good Health, Battle Creek, Mich.), 1938 Dec (Box 8)
      - 1939
        - "Nutrition Reform in U.S.A" ( Reform-Rundschau, Berlin, Germany), 1939 Jan (Box 8)
      - 1940
        - "Liquor Trade as an Economic Problem" ( Union Signal, Evanston, Ill.), 1940 Nov 2 (Box 8)
        - "I am Delighted with the Magazine," re International Student study of Alcohol Problem, 1940 Jun 30 (Box 8)
      - 1941
        - Chapter 14. Supply and Demand--Contd. (Box 8)
      - 1943
        - Letter to American Red Cross, dated Sept. 19, 1917 re including Tobacco in Soldier's Packages (Printed in The Narcotic Review, Chicago, Ill.), 1943 Jun (Box 8)
      - 1944
        - Letter evaluating Dr. Davenport's Contributions to Eugenics ( Eugenical News, N.Y.C.), 1944 Mar (Box 8)
      - 1947
        - Extract from last edition of "How to Live" ( Life & Health ), 1947 May (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous, Vol. I: "War and Peace", 1914 June 1 - 1921 December 31
    - War and Peace
      - 1914 (Box 8)
        - After the War, What? ( New York Times ) (Box 8)
      - 1915
        - Separate reprint with letter from Lord Bryce (Box 8)
          - Extracts from same ( Navy Yard American, Bremerton, Washington) (Box 8)
          - Abstract from same, ( The Stellar Ray, Detroit) (Box 8)
        - Introduction to "A Substitute for War" by Percy MacKaye (Box 8)
        - Reply to Henry Ford's invitation to join Peace Party on Oscar II ( Journal-Courier ) (Box 8)
      - 1916
        - Extracts from paper read at Conference on Real Preparedness, Washington, D.C. ( Evening Post ) (Box 8)
        - Interview at Battle Creek Sanitarium re Conference of Neutral Nations ( Battle Creek Enquirer ) (Box 8)
        - Call a Neutral Conference Now ( Independent ) (Box 8)
          - Reprint of same ( Bulletin No. 1, Amer. Neutral Conference Committee) (Box 8)
          - Extracts from same (Box 8)
            - Union, Springfield, Mass. (Box 8)
            - Evening Mail (Box 8)
            - Special Letter in Babson's Reports (Box 8)
        - Comment on Germany's Proposals of Peace ( World, New York) (Box 8)
      - 1917
        - Address before City Club of Rochester on Cut-Throat Competition in Armament ( Union Advertiser, Rochester, N.Y.) (Box 8)
          - Extracts from same ( Union, Schenectady) (Box 8)
        - Extracts from address before Women's Peace Party ( Union, New Haven) (Box 8)
        - Must Join Peace League if Formed, letter to Miss Leila Faye Secor of Amer. Neutral Conference Com., read at mtg. ( Herald, N.Y.) (Box 8)
        - U.S. Must Drop Isolation Policy ( Journal-Courier, New Haven) (Box 8)
          - Abstract of same ( Record Herald, Chicago) (Box 8)
        - German Plot Futile ( Register, New Haven) (Box 8)
        - Letter re plan to make $1,000,000,000 gift to France ( World, N.Y.C.) (Box 8)
        - Sensible War Economy, written for Com. on Public Safety, Boston, Mass. ( Jamaica Plains News ) (Box 8)
        - Extracts from address before Commonwealth Club, San Francisco, on International Competition after the War ( Examiner, San Francisco) (Box 8)
        - Extracts from address before Progressive Business Men's Club, Portland, Ore. on International Competition after the War ( Oregonian, Portland) (Box 8)
        - Extracts from address before Municipal League, Seattle, Wash. on Economic Problems of the War ( Post Intelligence, Seattle) (Box 8)
        - What We are Fighting For, address at Peace Dale Congregational Church ( Narragansett Times ) (Box 8)
        - War Problems at Home, from address at University of Washington, Seattle ( Sun, N.Y.) (Box 8)
        - Statement re what League of Nations will mean (Leaflet entitled "The World's Hope") (Box 8)
      - 1918
        - Abstract of address before mass meeting at First Methodist Episcopal Church, Jamestown, R.I. on Safeguards against Future World Wars ( Jamestown Morning Post ) (Box 8)
        - Extracts of addresses at meetings held by Natl. War Com. on Churches and Moral Aims of the War at Harrisburg, Pa. ( Patriot, Harrisburg) (Box 8)
        - Extracts from address before Annl. Mtg. of Hampden Assoc. of Congregational Churches & Ministers at Hope Church, Springfield, Mass. ( Springfield Daily Republican ) (Box 8)
        - A League of Nations an Absolute Necessity, sent out in mimeographed form by State Council of Defense in campaign on League to Enforce Peace (Box 8)
      - 1919
        - A League of Nations an Absolute Necessity, shortened form of same, sent out in broadside form by League to Enforce Peace (Box 8)
          - Reprint of same ( News, Detroit) (Box 8)
          - Extracts from same ( Eagle, Brooklyn) (Box 8)
          - Extracts from same ( Times, Bridgeport, Conn.) (Box 8)